JULIO PACHECO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

I am a charismatic person, always in the pursuit of knowledge. I spent 5 years working as an electrical engineer and was hungry for something more challenging. Life has taken me in many interesting turns, but I am never afraid of the unknown. Now I'm fully dedicating myself to pursuing a software engineering role.

CONTACT

- (646) 281-3134
- ✓ jpacheco0825@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/julio-pacheco-06958bb7/
- https://github.com/jpacheco008
- Portfolio

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, Javascript, VS Code, React
- Git, Github, Node.js, SQL, Express
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MoongooseODM
- Ruby, Ruby on Rails
- C#, Matlab, Java, C++

EDUCATION

New York Institute of Technology

SEP 2014 - MAY 2016

BS in computer and electrical engineering technology

PROJECTS

- Money Exchanger: Web app using third party API.
- Julio's Restaurant: Web app using a third party database, partial CRUD

EXPERIENCE

- General Assembly, Software Engineering Fellow OCT 2020 FEB 2021
 - Architected and built fully responsive front end web applications using HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, and third-party API integrations.
 - Applied knowledge of key languages and computer science concepts, including algorithms, to design and develop high quality and maintainable code.

PGE Engineering/BMH Engineering/Thomas Polise Consulting, Electrical Designer

JAN 2015 - JUN 2020

- Designed electrical, lighting, fire alarm, and power distribution floor plans and risers in accordance with the National Electrical Code and local jurisdiction guidelines.
- Performed site investigations to assess scope of work required and write job proposals.
- Coordinated with architects and contractors to resolve project changes, equipment submissions and RFIs in over 100 construction projects.

Netplus Consulting, Senior Field Technician

FEB 2015 - NOV 2015

- Managed security systems and IT issue tickets for over 50 clients providing them with solutions and business operations support.
- Established network infrastructure for new store locations and installed all necessary equipment for business operations.
- Built custom electronic systems solutions to accommodate multiple client needs.

US Navy, Pump Room Supervisor/Airport Shift Supervisor

FEB 2004 - JAN 2012

- Accountable for over 350,000 gallons of jet fuel and millions of dollars' worth of equipment in two aviation fuel pump rooms.
- Responsible for all aviation fuel equipment below deck system through-out the ship.
- Trained over 50 new personnel on airfield safety and procedures.